THOMAS HIGSON

ast updated October 2021





summary

I am a technical product manager with **15 years' experience** in software development, 6 of which in product roles. My background is in **web development and cloud infrastructure**

As a **certified agile practitioner**, I also enjoy helping each company I work with progress their agile transition

My passion is to solve problems, balancing strategic and creative thinking, to make new products that people love

qualifications

- PMI Agile Practitioner
- (pursuing) Cloud Digital Leader
- Certified training instructor
- Mental health first aider



B.Sc. in Computer Science, 2007

proficiencies

Methodologies

- Scrum
- Scrumban
- Kanban
- · Lean · SAFe

Tools

• Jira • Confluence

Concepts

- Microservice architecture
- Progressive Web Apps

Languages

- TypeSciptHTML
- CSS Sass

awards

- Silver award, Thales 2008
 International Innovation Awards
- Project award for excellence by the Ministry of Defence in 2008
- Highest MOD project feedback score of all UK Thales Land and Joint Systems projects
- Contribution to the Business, MBDA 2011 National Awards

career



Senior Product Manager Board Intelligence

since July 2021 (3 months)

I am the most senior product manager for Board Intelligence's primary **Software as a Service offering, worth £20 Million** in annual recurring revenue

Technologies

• AWS • Azure

• REST • OData

Kubernetes

Our mission is to keep ahead in our increasingly competitive marketplace by infusing our unique knowledge of productive board management into all our products

- Simplified the product offerings to reduce manual testing effort by 20%
- Established the needs of a £300k client and **demonstrated compliance against our roadmap**, resulting in them signing up ahead of the features being developed
- Built a strong relationship of trust with key stakeholders, making them comfortable trading requirements, even late into development



Product Manager Ocado Technology

March 2020 – July 2021 (**1 year, 4 months**)

I managed an agile team within Ocado's next generation grocery e-commerce solution

Considering ¾ of the UK workforce eat the same lunch every working day, our mission was to eliminate grocery tedium by making it effortless to find alternatives that align with your shopping interests, bringing greater satisfaction and better health

- Ranked the relative needs and priorities for a bespoke recommendations engine that outperformed the old engine across all metrics
- Improved discoverability of key user stories from 30% to 80%
- Helped the robotics team prioritise work to maximise value using value stream analysis

dyson

Technical Product Owner Dyson

September 2019 – March 2020 (6 months)

I helped identify the weak points and most valuable opportunities to prioritise platform work across a group of 9 scrum teams

Half of all the year's traffic is concentrated into the Christmas period; our mission was to ensure we could cope with this for 2019 peak trading

- We achieved zero downtime during the peak trading window for the first time in the site's history
- Migrated from a monolithic, unsupported, legacy identity management system to a modern, modular architecture, removing vendor lock-in and eliminating long-ongoing scaling issues
- Recognition from Which in their 2019 website rankings as the #6 electronics sales site, beating notable competition including Apple and Amazon



Engineering Lead General Dynamics

September 2017 – September 2019 (**2 years**)

I led a **research and development** group to better understand and solve the Ministry of Defence's problems with app development, integration, and deployment onto distributed military networks. Defence apps are traditionally hard to develop, requiring multi-million-pound investments into physical infrastructure and alignment with many moving dependencies. Our mission was to standardise and modernise military app development, opening defence up to wider industry

- Proved concepts for app integration and testing to reduce release time from 2 years to 3 months
- Introduced app management and separation technologies to reduce operational downtime by 70%
- Produced a cloud architecture to securely provide access to restricted technology



Engineering Manager **ZF TRW**

September 2016 – September 2017 (**1 year**)

I worked across multiple engineering teams to create a safety case for an automotive radar and camera fusion vision system

- Delivered safety cases for driving autonomy level 1 (hands on) applications
- Trained 40 engineers in safety engineering with Model Based Systems Engineering

MBDA

Principal Engineer

MBDA Systems

June 2009 – September 2016 (7 years, 3 months)

THALES

Software Engineer
Thales

September 2007 – June 2009 (1 year, 9 months)

For more information on my older roles, please see my portfolio website

interests

I am a keen martial artist and hold a license to teach Taekwondo for the United Kingdom Taekwondo Association Although no longer a developer, I like to keep my knowledge relevant with personal projects, such as:

- Small cloud native websites such as <u>this one</u> to host my CV
- Raspberry Pi projects, such as home automation systems and <u>Pi Holes</u>
- Selenium scripts to automate repetitive admin tasks